<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Daily Plant</string>
    <string name="expand_button_content_description">Provides more details on a plant</string>

    <string name="aloe_vera">Aloe Vera</string>
    <string name="ashwagandha">Ashwagandha</string>
    <string name="bilberry">Bilberry</string>
    <string name="bitter_melon">Bitter Melon</string>
    <string name="black_cohosh">Black Cohosh</string>
    <string name="calendula">Calendula</string>
    <string name="cats_claw">Cat\'s Claw</string>
    <string name="chamomile">Chamomile</string>
    <string name="echinacea">Echinacea</string>
    <string name="elderberry">Elderberry</string>
    <string name="ginkgo_biloba">Ginkgo Biloba</string>
    <string name="ginger">Ginger</string>
    <string name="ginseng">Ginseng</string>
    <string name="goldenseal">Goldenseal</string>
    <string name="hawthorn">Hawthorn</string>
    <string name="holy_basil">Holy Basil</string>
    <string name="horsetail">Horsetail</string>
    <string name="lavender">Lavender</string>
    <string name="licorice_root">Licorice Root</string>
    <string name="milk_thistle">Milk Thistle</string>
    <string name="nettle">Nettle</string>
    <string name="olive_leaf">Olive Leaf</string>
    <string name="peppermint">Peppermint</string>
    <string name="red_clover">Red Clover</string>
    <string name="reishi_mushroom">Reishi Mushroom</string>
    <string name="saint_johns_wort">Saint John\'s Wort</string>
    <string name="saw_palmetto">Saw Palmetto</string>
    <string name="turmeric">Turmeric</string>
    <string name="valerian">Valerian</string>
    <string name="yarrow">Yarrow</string>

    <string name="aloe_vera_description">
        Aloe Vera originates from the Arabian Peninsula and is a succulent plant with thick, fleshy leaves.
        The gel from the leaves is extracted and applied topically for skin healing or consumed to soothe digestive issues.
        Its effects are achieved through compounds like aloin, which promote healing and reduce inflammation.
    </string>

    <string name="ashwagandha_description">
        Ashwagandha is native to India and parts of Africa, featuring small green leaves and red berries.
        The root is dried, powdered, and consumed as a tea or in capsules.
        Its adaptogenic effects, reducing stress and improving energy, are due to the active compounds called withanolides.
    </string>

    <string name="bilberry_description">
        Bilberry is found in Europe and grows as a small shrub with dark blue berries.
        The berries are consumed fresh, dried, or in extracts for eye health and circulation.
        Its effects are due to anthocyanins, which improve blood vessel function and reduce inflammation.
    </string>

    <string name="bitter_melon_description">
        Bitter Melon is native to tropical regions of Asia and has an oblong, bumpy fruit.
        The fruit is typically juiced, cooked, or taken as a supplement to help regulate blood sugar.
        Its hypoglycemic effects are achieved by compounds like charantin and polypeptide-p, which mimic insulin.
    </string>

    <string name="black_cohosh_description">
        Black Cohosh originates from North America and is a tall plant with white flowers.
        The root is dried and used in tinctures or capsules to alleviate menopause symptoms.
        Its effects are believed to be due to triterpene glycosides, though the exact mechanism is not fully understood.
    </string>

    <string name="calendula_description">
        Calendula is native to the Mediterranean and has bright yellow to orange flowers.
        The flowers are dried and used in oils, creams, or teas for their anti-inflammatory and healing properties.
        The active compounds, such as flavonoids, help reduce inflammation and promote tissue repair.
    </string>

    <string name="cats_claw_description">
        Cat\'s Claw is found in the Amazon rainforest and features claw-shaped thorns on its vine.
        The bark and root are made into teas or extracts to boost the immune system and reduce inflammation.
        Its effects come from alkaloids like rhynchophylline, which modulate the immune response.
    </string>

    <string name="chamomile_description">
        Chamomile is native to Europe and Western Asia and has daisy-like white flowers.
        The dried flowers are steeped in tea or used in topical preparations to promote relaxation and digestion.
        Chamomile’s effects are primarily due to apigenin, which binds to receptors in the brain that reduce anxiety.
    </string>

    <string name="echinacea_description">
        Echinacea is native to North America and is characterized by its purple coneflowers.
        The roots and leaves are dried and taken as teas, tinctures, or supplements to enhance immune function.
        Echinacea works by increasing the production of white blood cells, although the exact mechanism is not fully known.
    </string>

    <string name="elderberry_description">
        Elderberry is native to Europe and North America and has clusters of small, dark berries.
        The berries are cooked into syrups or extracts to boost the immune system and alleviate cold and flu symptoms.
        Its effects are due to flavonoids, which reduce viral replication and inflammation.
    </string>

    <string name="ginkgo_biloba_description">
        Ginkgo Biloba originates from China and has fan-shaped leaves.
        The leaves are dried and consumed in teas or capsules to improve cognitive function and circulation.
        Its effects are thought to be caused by terpenoids and flavonoids, which enhance blood flow and act as antioxidants.
    </string>

    <string name="ginger_description">
        Ginger is native to Southeast Asia and has a knobby, underground stem (rhizome).
        The fresh or dried root is consumed as tea, in food, or in supplements to treat nausea and inflammation.
        Gingerol, its main bioactive compound, reduces nausea and has anti-inflammatory effects by blocking certain enzymes
    </string>

    <string name="ginseng_description">
        Ginseng is found in East Asia and North America, featuring a fleshy root.
        The root is dried and taken as tea or in capsules to reduce stress and boost energy.
        Its effects are due to ginsenosides, which act on the central nervous system to enhance physical and mental performance.
    </string>

    <string name="goldenseal_description">
        Goldenseal originates from North America and has bright yellow roots and small, green leaves.
        The root is dried and consumed in capsules or teas to treat infections and digestive disorders.
        Berberine, its active compound, has antimicrobial effects by inhibiting bacterial growth and supporting immune function.
    </string>

    <string name="hawthorn_description">
        Hawthorn is native to Europe, North America, and Asia, with red berries and thorny branches.
        The berries and leaves are dried and used in teas or extracts to support heart health.
        Its cardio-protective effects are due to flavonoids, which improve circulation and strengthen the heart muscle.
    </string>

    <string name="holy_basil_description">
        Holy Basil is native to India and has green or purple leaves with a strong aroma.
        The leaves are consumed as tea or in capsules to reduce stress and support respiratory health.
        Its effects come from eugenol and other compounds, which help reduce stress and inflammation through their antioxidant activity.
    </string>

    <string name="horsetail_description">
        Horsetail grows in temperate regions of Europe, North America, and Asia, with tall, jointed stems.
        The aerial parts are dried and consumed as tea or extracts to support bone, nail, and hair health.
        Its high silica content strengthens connective tissues, though the exact mechanism is not fully understood.
    </string>

    <string name="lavender_description">
        Lavender originates from the Mediterranean and features purple flowers with a calming fragrance.
        The flowers are distilled into essential oil or steeped in tea for relaxation and sleep support.
        The effects are due to linalool, a compound that influences neurotransmitters to promote calmness.
    </string>

    <string name="licorice_root_description">
        Licorice Root is native to Southern Europe and Western Asia, with long, slender roots.
        The root is dried and taken as tea, in capsules, or in tinctures for soothing digestion and respiratory issues.
        Its effects are due to glycyrrhizin, which has anti-inflammatory and immune-boosting properties.
    </string>

    <string name="milk_thistle_description">
        Milk Thistle is found in Mediterranean regions, characterized by its spiny leaves and purple flowers.
        The seeds are crushed and consumed as tea or in capsules to support liver health.
        Its active compound, silymarin, helps protect the liver by promoting cell regeneration and reducing oxidative stress.
    </string>

    <string name="nettle_description">
        Nettle is native to Europe, Asia, and North America, with stinging hairs on its leaves and stems.
        The leaves and roots are dried and made into teas or capsules to treat arthritis and allergies.
        Its effects are thought to come from anti-inflammatory compounds and histamine-blocking properties.
    </string>

    <string name="olive_leaf_description">
        Olive trees are native to the Mediterranean, with elongated green leaves.
        The leaves are dried and taken as tea or in extract form to support heart health and lower blood pressure.
        Its effects are attributed to oleuropein, which has antioxidant and anti-inflammatory properties.
    </string>

    <string name="peppermint_description">
        Peppermint is native to Europe and has fragrant, dark green leaves.
        The leaves are consumed as tea or in oil form to soothe digestive issues and improve respiratory health.
        Its effects are due to menthol, which relaxes muscles in the digestive tract and has a cooling effect on the skin.
    </string>

    <string name="red_clover_description">
        Red Clover is native to Europe and Asia, featuring pinkish-purple flower heads.
        The flowers are dried and consumed as tea or in capsules to support respiratory health and alleviate menopausal symptoms.
        Its effects are due to isoflavones, which mimic estrogen in the body and support hormone balance.
    </string>

    <string name="reishi_mushroom_description">
        Reishi Mushroom is found in East Asia and has a reddish-brown, kidney-shaped fruiting body.
        The mushroom is dried and consumed as tea or in capsules to boost immune function and reduce stress.
        Its effects come from polysaccharides, which enhance immune activity and promote relaxation.
    </string>

    <string name="saint_johns_wort_description">
        Saint John\'s Wort is native to Europe and has bright yellow flowers.
        The flowers and leaves are dried and taken as tea or in capsules to treat depression and nerve pain.
        Its effects are thought to be due to hypericin and hyperforin, which influence serotonin levels in the brain.
    </string>

    <string name="saw_palmetto_description">
        Saw Palmetto originates from the Southeastern United States and features fan-shaped leaves and dark berries.
        The berries are dried and taken in capsules or extracts to support prostate health.
        Its effects are believed to come from fatty acids and phytosterols, which reduce inflammation and influence hormone levels.
    </string>

    <string name="turmeric_description">
        Turmeric is native to South Asia and has a bright orange root.
        The root is dried and ground into powder, consumed in food, tea, or supplements to reduce inflammation.
        Curcumin, the active compound, inhibits molecules that play a role in inflammation, providing relief for joint and digestive issues.
    </string>

    <string name="valerian_description">
        Valerian is native to Europe and Asia and has small white or pink flowers.
        The root is dried and consumed as tea or in capsules to promote relaxation and improve sleep.
        Its effects are believed to come from valerenic acid, which affects GABA receptors in the brain to reduce anxiety.
    </string>

    <string name="yarrow_description">
        Yarrow is native to Europe and Asia, with feathery leaves and clusters of white flowers.
        The aerial parts are dried and used as tea or in poultices to treat wounds and digestive issues.
        Its effects are due to compounds like flavonoids and salicylic acid, which reduce inflammation and support healing.
    </string>
</resources>